<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How to on BornAgain</title>
    <link>https://www.bornagainproject.org/documentation/howto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How to on BornAgain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.bornagainproject.org/documentation/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Get announcements</title>
      <link>https://www.bornagainproject.org/documentation/howto/announcements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bornagainproject.org/documentation/howto/announcements/</guid>
      <description>How to get announcements Subscribe to the mailing list BornAgain announcements. It is moderated, and has very low traffic. It is used to announce new releases and workshops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solve known problems</title>
      <link>https://www.bornagainproject.org/documentation/howto/troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bornagainproject.org/documentation/howto/troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>How to solve known problems  Windows specific  Missing api-ms-win-crt-runtime-l1-1-0.dll   MacOS specific  Incompatible library version of libgsl.0.dylib   Building from source on Linux  Configuration (cmake) fails Qt5 configuration problems Compilation (make) fails   Common  Functional test (ctest) fails Fatal Python error: PyThreadState_Get: no current thread     Windows specific Missing api-ms-win-crt-runtime-l1-1-0.dll On some Windows machines, you might get the message &amp;ldquo;The program can&amp;rsquo;t start because api-ms-win-crt-runtime-l1-1-0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request help or report bugs</title>
      <link>https://www.bornagainproject.org/documentation/howto/get-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bornagainproject.org/documentation/howto/get-help/</guid>
      <description>Let us know if you encounter a problem during installation or while running BornAgain or if you have a question related to BornAgain models.
Please use GitHub Issue System for all kind of problems/questions you might have. This will help us to track user requests and set our priorities.
Let us know GitHub Issue System  report bug request help with problems in installing or running BornAgain request a new feature pose a question about BornAgain API or model implementations  Create issue    Especially for bug reports, supply all relevant information that may help us to analyse the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribute to this documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.bornagainproject.org/documentation/howto/contribute-to-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bornagainproject.org/documentation/howto/contribute-to-documentation/</guid>
      <description>How to contribute to this documentation Here we explain how to edit this documentation locally and submit changes for online publication.
General information Our web site repository contains two branches. Master branch contains markdown content of the site, gh-pages branch contains static html of the site. Hugo static site generator is used to produce html content from markdown pages.
GitHub is configured to host content of gh-pages branch at this address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cite BornAgain</title>
      <link>https://www.bornagainproject.org/documentation/howto/cite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.bornagainproject.org/documentation/howto/cite/</guid>
      <description>How to cite BornAgain The canonical reference for BornAgain is the journal article:
 Gennady Pospelov, Walter Van Herck, Jan Burle, Juan M. Carmona Loaiza, Céline Durniak, Jonathan M. Fisher, Marina Ganeva, Dmitry Yurov and Joachim Wuttke:
BornAgain: software for simulating and fitting grazing-incidence small- angle scattering
J. Appl. Cryst. 53, 262–276 (2020)
 Use of the software should additionally be documented by citing a specific version thereof:
 BornAgain — Software for simulating and fitting X-ray and neutron small-angle scattering at grazing incidence,</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>